Iman Norouzi

1 17 Myoora road, Toorak 3142, Australia, (+61) 403 509 702, iman.norouzy@gmail.com

KEY SKILLS

JAVA / NodeJS / Angular / React / SQL / MySql / Oracle / AngularJS / Bootstrap / CSS / SpringBoot / REST / Postgres / AWS / C / C++ / PHP / Shell programming / Linux / HTML5 / Dropwizard / Javascript / Jquery / CSS / REST / Nginx

I'M EXPERT IN

- Software Architecture, Software Development
- Programming (Enterprise application, Mobile, APIs and Backend, Web)
- IT Service Management, Technical support
- Data Mining
- Telecommunication, BSS

EDUCATION

2011-2013

Information Technology Engineering MSc, University of Tehran, Iran, GPA:80% **2006-2010**

Medical Information Technology Engineering BSc, University of Isfahan, Iran

SUMMARY

A practiced IT professional with B.Sc. In IT Engineering and M.Sc. in Medical IT Engineering. I have 8 years of experience in web-based and enterprise software development. I'm an expert in Java, NodeJs, React, and Angular. I have also good knowledge of mobile programming platforms.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Metro Trains Melbourne | Jul 2017 - Current

Metro Trains Melbourne, often known simply as Metro, is the franchise operator of the electrified suburban passenger service on the Melbourne rail network.

Key responsibilities

- Design and development of Passenger Information and Train Control Softwares.
- Communicating with users and train controllers to know the requirements and create solutions based on their needs.
- Upgrade and enhancement of various existing Systems.
- Connecting software to other systems in production after development, testing, and deployment.
- Integration, release and maintenance of developed applications.

Achievement

- I developed a new Passenger Information Display (PID) application in **react/Java** which replaced all the third-party softwares. The application generates train information and displays it on the screens in Metro stations.
- I was one of two developers of a Fault Management System. It is launched successfully and made a big change in the process of tracing and rectifying train faults. Technologies used for this are **NodeJs** and **Angular 8** connected to a **Postgres DB**.
- I am the front-end developer of Real Time Position of Trains System. It delivers reports and real-time positions of the trains to help train controllers assign trains to services. This application is launched successfully. This is a **Java**, **Angular 8** project.
- I have delivered at least five other small to medium size projects to help MTM processes which are mostly written in **Java** (Native, **SpringBoot**, and **dropwizard**).

Software Engineer, BRTel Co | Sep 2016 - Mar 2017

BRTel is a leading Telecommunications service and solution.

Key responsibilities

- Design and development of web-based and enterprise applications.
- Automating tasks using Shell Script

Achievement

 Developed a reporting application with a very customized design to overcome the performance problems with big datasets. This application had user-friendly UI to represent outcomes in a meaningful way. It replaced the old manual processes and added

- much value by covering new requirements. (Java, Oracle, Javascript, CSS, HTML5).
- Created solutions for receiving real-time data from call centers and evaluating call center agents based on received data. (Shell scripts, Java APIs)

Jun 2016 – Present, Android Developer, 780 Co, Tehran, Iran (part time)

*780# is the most famous billing android application in Iran which is programmed for daily payments such as bill payments, charging mobile line, charities and similar functionalities.

Key Responsibilities:

- Development (Java, Android SDK, JSON, Security methodologies, Git and subversion, ...)
- Technical support, Issue investigation and trouble shouting
- Technical design, technical solution design
- End-to-End testing and unit testing

Achievement:

• Increasing the number of users by adding features like balance of bank account inquiry and mobile auto recharge.

Software engineer, Tecnotree Corporation | Sep 2014 – May 2016

Tecnotree is a Finnish Public Limited Company and it is a global provider of Telecom IT solutions.

Key responsibilities

- Technical implementation of deliverable items, such as fixes, releases and patches.
- Improving the performance of big real-time applications.
- Integration with other operating applications.

Achievements

- Delivered Auction Portal, a web-based project successfully. It was an online auction software to help the company put golden numbers in an auction. (Java, Oracle, Javascript, JQuery, CSS, HTML5, Weblogic)
- Implemented a data learning module for "Loyalty application" in which I used data mining methods to predict customer behavior and suggest plans for Loyalty application. (Java, Matlab)

Software Engineer, Duran Software Group | Aug 2012 - Feb 2014

DOURAN Information Technologies is a successful IT company in the field of ERP.

Key responsibilities

- Development of ERP systems and supporting ERP components.
- Testing deliverable items and tuning possible performance issues.

Achievement

- Delivered two complex ERP subsystems, Attendance, and Payroll.
 (Java Native, Oracle, Company Java based UI framework, JReport)
- Integrated Attendance subsystem with the Payroll subsystem and then with Accounting subsystem. (Java, Oracle)

REFERENCES